CARLA SCHERER

Data Science & Al

São Paulo, BR +55 51 993267470 carlatscherer@gmail.com Linked-In: carla-scherer-a4793b93/ GitHub: carlascherer

WHO AM I

I have a masters degree in Engineering with a focus on mathematical modelling of Structures and I have been studying to specialize in Data Science/Al field. I have professional experience working with OCR/Al solutions using IBM Watson and chat/voice bots development for the financial sector. I am also certified in some Clouds, like Azure and Google. I appreciate working with technology because I get the chance to learn something new every day. It also enables me to help to solve problems using logic and exact sciences, something that motivates me. I am curious and like to understand how things work and why they are as they are. I also learn very fast because I am engaged and always try to push myself out of my comfort zone.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accenture / Software Engineering Analyst

10/2020-Now

- Development of OCR/AI model to extract information of non-structured documents (text documents)
- Development/improvement of python scripts for text mining
- Model improvement based on tracking of metrics
- Development of virtual assistants for the finance sector
- Design and implementation of the conversation flows and NLP entities and intents
- Development of python cloud functions to manipulate data and integrate the bot with external APIs

RS Highways Company / CORSAN / Civil Engineer

07/2018-09/2020 - 02/2015-02/2016

- Coordination of engineering services
- Elaboration of analysis reports and budgets using VBA
- Automation of day-to-day engineering tasks

EDUCATION

UFRGS, MSc. Civil Eng. - Structures 2016-2018

UFRGS, Civil Eng. | Electrical Eng. (Incomp.) 2009-2013 | 2007-2009

DIGITAL HOUSE, Full Stack Web Dev. | Data Science 2020-2021 | 2021-2021

Languages/Libraries

- Python
- Pandas/Numpy
- Scikit-learn
- SQL
- JavaScript
- Flask
- HTML/CSS

Tools

- GCP/Azure
- DialogFlow
- Watson KS
- GCP AutoML
- Power Bl
- Git/GitHub
- Kubernetes
- Excel

Knowledge

- Math./Stats.
- NLP/NLU
- Cloud
- OCR/AI
- DevOps, CI/CD

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Colaboration
- Resilience
- Flexibility
- Creativity

